const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"A 9-year-old boy presents to the emergency department with left-sided hemiplegia. There is no history of head trauma to explain this presentation. If he had been diagnosed with anemia a few months ago, which of the following accounts for hemiplegia?","answers":[{"option":"Thrombotic thrombocytopenic purpura","bool":false},{"option":"Multiple myeloma","bool":false},{"option":"Thalassemia","bool":false},{"option":"Sickle cell anemia","bool":true},{"option":"Fainting due to anemia","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Which of the following is the diagnostic test for Rh incompatibility?","answers":[{"option":"Fetal middle cerebral arterial (MCA) doppler","bool":false},{"option":"Indirect Coombs test","bool":true},{"option":"Direct Coombs test","bool":false},{"option":"Chorionic villus sampling","bool":false},{"option":"Amniocentesis","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Bernard-Soulier is an inherited disease having giant, non-functional platelets with thrombocytopenia. What is the inheritance pattern of this disease?","answers":[{"option":"Autosomal dominant","bool":false},{"option":"Mitochondrial inheritance","bool":false},{"option":"X-linked recessive","bool":false},{"option":"Autosomal recessive","bool":true},{"option":"X-linked dominant","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Which one of the following constituents is present in hemoglobin A (HbA)?","answers":[{"option":"2 alpha and 2 gamma chains","bool":false},{"option":"2 delta and 2 gamma chains","bool":false},{"option":"2 alpha and 2 beta chains","bool":true},{"option":"2 alpha and 2 delta chains","bool":false},{"option":"2 zeta and 2 epsilon chains","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Which one of the following is the most common type of Hodgkin lymphoma?","answers":[{"option":"Nodular sclerosis","bool":true},{"option":"Nodular lymphocyte predominant","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphocyte rich","bool":false},{"option":"Mixed cellularity","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphocyte depleted","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Which component of blood is best for transfusion in case of multiple coagulation factor deficiencies?","answers":[{"option":"Pooled platelets","bool":false},{"option":"Whole blood","bool":false},{"option":"Fresh frozen plasma","bool":true},{"option":"Cryoprecipitate","bool":false},{"option":"Packed red cells","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Which one of the following is used as an antidote for heparin?","answers":[{"option":"Fresh frozen plasma (FFP)","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin C","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin K","bool":false},{"option":"Succimer","bool":false},{"option":"Protamine sulfate","bool":true}]},{"id":7,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Which of the following blood cells have phagocytic activity?","answers":[{"option":"Reticulocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Fibroblasts","bool":false},{"option":"Neutrophils","bool":true},{"option":"Megakaryocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Platelets","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"What is the mechanism of action of tacrolimus?","answers":[{"option":"Destruction of T-cells","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of calcineurin","bool":true},{"option":"Inhibition of inosine monophosphate dehydrogenase","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of purine synthesis","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of IL-2 action","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"A 35-year-old man with a history of intravenous (IV) drug abuse has generalized lymphadenopathy. Which of the following tests would help in finding the cause of his lymphadenopathy?","answers":[{"option":"Ultrasonography","bool":false},{"option":"Bone marrow biopsy","bool":false},{"option":"HIV serology","bool":true},{"option":"Histopathology","bool":false},{"option":"Complete blood count (CBC)","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Vitamin K is given as an antidote to warfarin therapy. How long do clotting factors take to return to their normal levels after the administration of vitamin K?","answers":[{"option":"6 minutes","bool":false},{"option":"6 days","bool":false},{"option":"6 hours","bool":false},{"option":"24 hours","bool":true},{"option":"48 hours","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"What is the most common gene mutation in alpha thalassemia?","answers":[{"option":"Splice mutation","bool":false},{"option":"Nonsense mutation","bool":false},{"option":"Frameshift mutation","bool":false},{"option":"Gene deletion","bool":true},{"option":"Missense mutation","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Which drug acts as an inhibitor of the IL-2 receptor?","answers":[{"option":"Rapamycin","bool":false},{"option":"Cetuximab","bool":false},{"option":"Abciximab","bool":false},{"option":"Basiliximab","bool":true},{"option":"Bevacizumab","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"A patient undergoing treatment with heparin suddenly develops heparin-induced thrombocytopenia (HIT). Which of the following routes of management should be used to treat the patient?","answers":[{"option":"Cryoprecipitate or factor VIII","bool":false},{"option":"Desmopressin and tranexamic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Bivalirudin and dabigatran infusion","bool":true},{"option":"Continue heparin therapy","bool":false},{"option":"Apixaban infusion","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Which of the following disorders can result in hydrops fetalis?","answers":[{"option":"Hemoglobin H disease","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha-thalassemia minor","bool":false},{"option":"Beta-thalassemia minor","bool":false},{"option":"Beta-thalassemia major","bool":false},{"option":"Hemoglobin Barts disease","bool":true}]},{"id":15,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Which of the following should not be used in the treatment of disseminated intravascular coagulation (DIC)?","answers":[{"option":"Antifibrinolytics","bool":true},{"option":"Cryoprecipitate","bool":false},{"option":"Fresh frozen plasma","bool":false},{"option":"Platelets","bool":false},{"option":"Heparin","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Under section 361 PPC, kidnapping consists of taking a minor from his/her lawful guardian without the consent of the guardian. What is the age of cut-off?","answers":[{"option":"14 years if male and 16 years if female","bool":true},{"option":"14 years for both male and female","bool":false},{"option":"16 years for both male and female","bool":false},{"option":"16 years if male and 18 years if female","bool":false},{"option":"18 years if female and 16 years if male","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"What percentage of the population needs to be immune to develop herd immunity against measles?","answers":[{"option":"90%","bool":false},{"option":"95%","bool":true},{"option":"75%","bool":false},{"option":"50%","bool":false},{"option":"85%","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"During the medicolegal autopsy of a man who died in a house fire, it is noted that the sphenoparietal suture in the skull is closed. What is the approximate age of this body at the time of death?","answers":[{"option":"60 years","bool":false},{"option":"35 years","bool":false},{"option":"50 years","bool":false},{"option":"70 years","bool":true},{"option":"40 years","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"A female presented with gingival bleeding, fever, and headache to the outpatient department (OPD). Her lab results showed normal partial thromboplastin time (PTT) and prothrombin time (PT) but increased bleeding time. Her blood smear showed the presence of schistocytes. Which one is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Immune thrombocytopenia","bool":false},{"option":"Disseminated intravascular coagulation","bool":false},{"option":"Thrombotic thrombocytopenic purpura","bool":true},{"option":"Hemophilia","bool":false},{"option":"von Willebrand disease","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Which joint is most commonly checked via X-ray to check bone age for precocious puberty?","answers":[{"option":"Shoulder","bool":false},{"option":"Knee","bool":false},{"option":"Wrist","bool":true},{"option":"Ankle","bool":false},{"option":"Hip","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Which of the following diseases is correctly paired with their characteristic marker?","answers":[{"option":"G6PD - Heinz bodies","bool":true},{"option":"Sickle cell disease - target cells","bool":false},{"option":"Myelofibrosis - spherocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin B12 deficiency - tear drop cells","bool":false},{"option":"Pyruvate kinase deficiency - hemoglobin crystals in RBCs","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Which of the following substances is a strong activator of macrophage?","answers":[{"option":"IL-10","bool":false},{"option":"IL-4","bool":false},{"option":"Interferon-gamma","bool":true},{"option":"Vascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF)","bool":false},{"option":"Tumor growth factor (TGF)","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"A 4-year-old boy is brought to the emergency room with a painful swollen right knee. The parents give a history of mild trauma, with the child falling from standing height. The knee is visibly swollen, bluish in color and movement is restricted due to pain. The parents also report a history of prolonged bleeding following his circumcision. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Septic arthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Von Willebrand disease","bool":false},{"option":"Bernard-Soulier syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Essential thrombocytosis","bool":false},{"option":"Hemophilia A","bool":true}]},{"id":24,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Maximum number of Reed-Sternberg cells are seen in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Lymphocyte depleted Hodgkin lymphoma","bool":true},{"option":"Mixed cellularity Hodgkin lymphoma","bool":false},{"option":"Nodular sclerosis Hodgkin lymphoma","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphocyte predominant Hodgkin lymphoma","bool":false},{"option":"Burkitt Lymphoma","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Which of the following is not an adverse effect of transfusion?","answers":[{"option":"Anaphylaxis","bool":false},{"option":"Autoimmune hemolytic anemia","bool":true},{"option":"Febrile reaction","bool":false},{"option":"Delayed hemolytic reaction","bool":false},{"option":"Acute hemolytic reaction","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"A 25-year-old man is being transfused with whole blood. Suddenly, he develops a fever of 38.5°C associated with chills and flushing. Blood is oozing from the cannula site. What kind of transfusion reaction is it?","answers":[{"option":"Allergic reaction","bool":false},{"option":"Acute hemolytic transfusion reaction","bool":true},{"option":"Delayed hemolytic transfusion reaction","bool":false},{"option":"Post transfusion purpura","bool":false},{"option":"Febrile non-hemolytic transfusion reaction","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Which of the following groups of drugs is not used for the treatment of thrombosis?","answers":[{"option":"Antifibrinolytics","bool":true},{"option":"Fibrinolytics","bool":false},{"option":"Thrombin inhibitors","bool":false},{"option":"Anticoagulants","bool":false},{"option":"Antiplatelet drugs","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"What is the definitive treatment for thalassemia major?","answers":[{"option":"Iron chelation therapy","bool":false},{"option":"Blood transfusion","bool":false},{"option":"Bone marrow transplantation","bool":true},{"option":"Iron supplementation","bool":false},{"option":"Cryotherapy","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Sideroblastic anemia is NOT associated with which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Vitamin B6 deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Alcohol poisoning","bool":false},{"option":"TB patient undergoing isoniazid therapy","bool":false},{"option":"Copper deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Iron deficiency","bool":true}]},{"id":30,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"A blood film shows hypochromic and microcytic red blood cells with poikilocytosis. What is the diagnosis based on this appearance?","answers":[{"option":"Hereditary spherocytosis","bool":false},{"option":"Aplastic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Sickle cell anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Iron deficiency anemia","bool":true},{"option":"Sideroblastic anemia","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"What is the most common cause of generalized lymphadenopathy?","answers":[{"option":"Fungal infection","bool":false},{"option":"Drug hypersensitivity","bool":false},{"option":"Systemic lupus erythematosus","bool":false},{"option":"Viral infection","bool":true},{"option":"Sarcoidosis","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Mild hypochromic microcytic anemia is associated with which of the following pathologies?","answers":[{"option":"Vitamin B12 deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha-thalassemia minor","bool":true},{"option":"Beta-thalassemia major","bool":false},{"option":"Diamond-Blackfan anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hemoglobin H disease","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Vitamin B12 deficiency is associated with which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Microcytic hypochromic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Pernicious anemia","bool":true},{"option":"Hereditary spherocytosis","bool":false},{"option":"Sickle cell disease","bool":false},{"option":"Sideroblastic anemia","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"When is the measles-1 vaccine administered?","answers":[{"option":"9 months","bool":true},{"option":"At birth","bool":false},{"option":"12 months","bool":false},{"option":"10 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"14 weeks","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Spread to the testicles and central nervous system is characteristic of which of the following neoplasias?","answers":[{"option":"Mantle cell lymphoma","bool":false},{"option":"Acute lymphoblastic leukemia","bool":true},{"option":"Burkitt lymphoma","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic myelogenous leukemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hairy cell leukemia","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"A patient complains of repeated instances of intense itching after a hot shower. Which condition is responsible for this?","answers":[{"option":"Myelofibrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Thrombotic thrombocytopenic purpura","bool":false},{"option":"Essential thrombocytopenia","bool":false},{"option":"Polycythemia vera","bool":true},{"option":"Burkitt lymphoma","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Stony hard lymph node is mostly suggestive of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Inflammation","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphoma","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Infection","bool":false},{"option":"Malignancy","bool":true}]},{"id":38,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Patients with severe liver disease are most likely to develop which of the following pathological findings?","answers":[{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Normal PT and APTT","bool":false},{"option":"Patient will be unresponsive to vitamin K injection","bool":true},{"option":"Defect in Gp1B receptors of platelets","bool":false},{"option":"Increased bleeding time","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"What is the most common condition leading to disseminated intravascular coagulation (DIC) in hospitalized patients?","answers":[{"option":"Vascular aneurysms","bool":false},{"option":"Malignancy","bool":false},{"option":"Trauma","bool":false},{"option":"Severe infection","bool":true},{"option":"Snake bite","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Which iron preparation can be given only by the intravenous route?","answers":[{"option":"Ferrous fumarate","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium ferrous gluconate complex","bool":false},{"option":"Ferrous gluconate dessicated","bool":false},{"option":"Iron fructose complex","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium ferric gluconate complex","bool":true}]},{"id":41,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Which of the following is the most commonly encountered pattern of fingerprints?","answers":[{"option":"Accidental","bool":false},{"option":"Loop","bool":true},{"option":"Whorl","bool":false},{"option":"Composite","bool":false},{"option":"Arch","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Which of the following shows intravascular hemolysis?","answers":[{"option":"Warm immune hemolytic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hereditary elliptocytosis","bool":false},{"option":"Sickle cell disease","bool":false},{"option":"Paroxysmal nocturnal hemoglobinuria","bool":true},{"option":"Hereditary spherocytosis","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Phenytoin decreases the action of warfarin by which of the following mechanisms?","answers":[{"option":"Increases renal clearance","bool":false},{"option":"Displaces warfarin from plasma proteins","bool":false},{"option":"Enhances warfarin metabolism","bool":true},{"option":"Inhibits intestinal absorption","bool":false},{"option":"Increases clotting factor synthesis","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"A 4-year-old male child is being evaluated for a bleeding disorder. Family history reveals that his maternal uncle had a similar disorder, but his mother and father had no such problem. What is the mode of transmission of the bleeding disorder in this child?","answers":[{"option":"Co-dominant","bool":false},{"option":"X-linked recessive","bool":true},{"option":"Autosomal recessive","bool":false},{"option":"Autosomal dominant","bool":false},{"option":"X-linked dominant","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Which condition shows both arterial and venous thrombosis?","answers":[{"option":"Protein S deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Antiphospholipid antibody syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Protein C deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Antithrombin deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Factor V Leiden mutation","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Which of the following is not true for leukemoid reaction?","answers":[{"option":"May involve neutrophils, eosinophils and lymphocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Absolute leukocyte count usually exceeds 25,000/mm3","bool":false},{"option":"It is very similar to chronic myelogenous leukemia","bool":false},{"option":"Normal bone marrow response to cytokines released by cells in infection","bool":false},{"option":"Leukocyte alkaline phosphatase (LAP) score is decreased","bool":true}]},{"id":47,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Monocytosis is seen in which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Sterile inflammation","bool":false},{"option":"Pemphigus","bool":false},{"option":"Bordetella pertussis","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculosis","bool":true},{"option":"Vasculitis","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"On palpation, the supraclavicular lymph nodes of a 50-year-old man feel stony hard. Which of the following is the most likely underlying cause?","answers":[{"option":"Tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphoma","bool":false},{"option":"Infection","bool":false},{"option":"Inflammation","bool":false},{"option":"Malignancy","bool":true}]},{"id":49,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"What is the literal translation of the legal term 'corpus delicti'?","answers":[{"option":"Weapon of choice","bool":false},{"option":"The will of the deceased","bool":false},{"option":"Reason of the murder","bool":false},{"option":"Body of the crime","bool":true},{"option":"Degree of the crime","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"A 75-year-old man presents to the hospital with generalized painless lymphadenopathy. Laboratory findings reveal a white blood cell count of 20,000 cells/mm³. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Hairy cell leukemia","bool":false},{"option":"Acute lymphoblastic leukemia","bool":false},{"option":"Myelodysplastic syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic lymphocytic leukemia","bool":true},{"option":"Myelofibrosis","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"A 7-year-old child presents to the outpatient department with his mother, with complaints of weight loss, fever, pallor, and bleeding over the body for three weeks. On examination, there is generalized lymphadenopathy with hepatosplenomegaly. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Aplastic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Idiopathic thrombocytopenic purpura","bool":false},{"option":"Thalassemia","bool":false},{"option":"Acute lymphoblastic leukemia","bool":true},{"option":"Sickle cell anemia","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Which of the following causes extravascular hemolysis?","answers":[{"option":"Mechanical injury","bool":false},{"option":"Complement fixation","bool":false},{"option":"Falciparum malaria","bool":false},{"option":"Exogenous toxic factor","bool":false},{"option":"When red blood cells become less deformable","bool":true}]},{"id":53,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Which of the following agents is used in the treatment of vitamin B12 deficiency?","answers":[{"option":"Hydroxycobalamin","bool":true},{"option":"Folate","bool":false},{"option":"Methylcobalamin","bool":false},{"option":"Menadione","bool":false},{"option":"Retinol","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Which of the following is the cause of atypical hemolytic uremic syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Decreased levels of ADAMTS13","bool":false},{"option":"Complement factor H deficiency","bool":true},{"option":"Systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE)","bool":false},{"option":"Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV)","bool":false},{"option":"Escherichia coli (E. coli)","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Tetanus exotoxin treated with formalin is an example of which type of vaccine?","answers":[{"option":"Toxoid vaccine","bool":true},{"option":"Killed vaccine","bool":false},{"option":"Subunit vaccine","bool":false},{"option":"Polysaccharide vaccine","bool":false},{"option":"Live attenuated vaccine","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Which of the following is an example of live attenuated vaccine?","answers":[{"option":"Measles","bool":true},{"option":"Cholera","bool":false},{"option":"Diphtheria","bool":false},{"option":"Pertussis","bool":false},{"option":"Rabies","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"What is the most likely gastrointestinal manifestation of acute graft-versus-host disease (GVHD)?","answers":[{"option":"Constipation","bool":false},{"option":"Dysphagia","bool":false},{"option":"Vomiting","bool":false},{"option":"Diarrhea","bool":true},{"option":"Jaundice","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Why are patients with polycythemia vera predisposed to thrombotic events?","answers":[{"option":"Endothelial damage","bool":false},{"option":"Hypercoagulability","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperviscosity of blood","bool":true},{"option":"Stasis","bool":false},{"option":"Vessel congestion","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Through which of the following bones age and sex determination of a skeleton can be determined?","answers":[{"option":"Radius and ulna","bool":false},{"option":"Vertebrae","bool":false},{"option":"Ribs","bool":false},{"option":"Metacarpals","bool":false},{"option":"Skull and mandible","bool":true}]},{"id":60,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"What is cheiloscopy used for?","answers":[{"option":"Identification of humans based on lip prints","bool":true},{"option":"Identification of humans based on finger prints","bool":false},{"option":"Identification of humans based on bite patterns","bool":false},{"option":"Identification of humans based on hand prints","bool":false},{"option":"Identification of humans based on foot prints","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"BCR-ABL fusion gene product is seen in which of the following leukemias?","answers":[{"option":"T-cell leukemia","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic myelogenous leukemia","bool":true},{"option":"Hairy cell leukemia","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic lymphocytic leukemia","bool":false},{"option":"Acute myeloid leukemia","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"The activation of the extrinsic coagulation system occurs with the release of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Tissue thromboplastin","bool":true},{"option":"Adenosine diphosphate (ADP)","bool":false},{"option":"Von Willebrand factor (vWF)","bool":false},{"option":"High-molecular-weight kininogen","bool":false},{"option":"Subendothelial collagen","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Which of the following is done to ensure that a research project has no errors?","answers":[{"option":"Devise a hypothesis","bool":false},{"option":"Conduct a pilot study","bool":true},{"option":"Select a sample size","bool":false},{"option":"Collect statistical data","bool":false},{"option":"Carry out a literature review","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"A 12-year-old boy presents to the clinic because he is passing cola-colored urine for 5 days. He was diagnosed with malaria 2 weeks ago and is taking chloroquine. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Hereditary spherocytosis","bool":false},{"option":"Megaloblastic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Aplastic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase deficiency","bool":true},{"option":"Iron deficiency anemia","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Which of the following can reverse the toxic effects of heparin?","answers":[{"option":"Alkylating agent","bool":false},{"option":"Clopidogrel","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin K","bool":false},{"option":"Protamine sulfate","bool":true},{"option":"Low molecular weight heparin","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Which of the following is not a complication of a massive blood transfusion?","answers":[{"option":"Hyperkalemia","bool":false},{"option":"Congestive heart failure","bool":false},{"option":"Volume overload","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothermia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypercalcemia","bool":true}]},{"id":67,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"A 35-year-old man presents to the clinic with easy fatigability and weakness. Spherocytes can be seen on peripheral blood smear. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Hereditary spherocytosis","bool":true},{"option":"Megaloblastic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Iron deficiency anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Anemia of chronic disease","bool":false},{"option":"Sickle cell anemia","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Which of the following would not cause intravascular hemolysis?","answers":[{"option":"Thrombotic thrombocytopenic purpura","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Systemic lupus erythematosus","bool":true},{"option":"Disseminated intravascular coagulation","bool":false},{"option":"Paroxysmal nocturnal hemoglobinuria","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Which of the following conditions is associated with the Philadelphia chromosome?","answers":[{"option":"Chronic myeloid leukemia","bool":true},{"option":"Acute lymphoblastic leukemia","bool":false},{"option":"Primary myelofibrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute myeloid leukemia","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic lymphocytic leukemia","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"A 26-year-old male presents to the clinic with enlarged lymph nodes in the neck, night sweats, and unexplained weight loss over the past few months. He reports intermittent low-grade fever and generalized fatigue. A physical examination reveals painless, firm, rubbery lymph nodes in the cervical region. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Non-Hodgkin lymphoma","bool":false},{"option":"Hodgkin lymphoma","bool":true},{"option":"Tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL)","bool":false},{"option":"Sarcoidosis","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"A 30-year-old male is brought to the emergency department after being bitten by a snake while hiking. He complains of severe pain and swelling at the site of the snakebite and a widespread rash all over his body. Laboratory tests reveal deranged prothrombin time (PT), activated partial thromboplastin time (aPTT), and a low platelet count. What is the initial management of this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Administer antivenom","bool":false},{"option":"Apply a tourniquet above the snakebite site","bool":false},{"option":"Administer pain relievers","bool":false},{"option":"Start antibiotics","bool":false},{"option":"Start intravenous fluids","bool":true}]},{"id":72,"info":"3rd-year/hematology/2018","question":"Auer rods are typically seen in which type of hematological malignancy?","answers":[{"option":"Chronic lymphocytic leukemia (CLL)","bool":false},{"option":"Hodgkin lymphoma","bool":false},{"option":"Acute myeloid leukemia (AML)","bool":true},{"option":"Non-Hodgkin lymphoma (NHL)","bool":false},{"option":"Multiple myeloma","bool":false}]}]
export default arr